http://www.michedcu.org/privacy-policy

Login to Online Banking
Privacy Policy
Home > Privacy Policy
FACTS
What does Michigan Educational Credit Union do with your personal information?
Why?
Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some, but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.
What?
The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the products or service you have with us. This information can include:
Social Security Number and income
Account balances and payment history
Credit history and credit scores
When you are no longer our member, we may continue to share your information as described in this notice.
How?
All financial companies need to share members' and other non-member consumers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their members' and other non-member consumers’ personal information; the reasons MECU chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
Reasons we can share your personal information
Does Michigan Educational Credit Union share?
Can you limit this sharing?
For our everyday business purposes: such as to process your transaction, maintain your accounts(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus
YES
NO
For our marketing purposes: to offer our products and services to you
YES
NO
For joint marketing with other financial companies
YES
NO
For our affiliates' everyday business purposes: information about your transactions and experiences
NO
N/A
For our affiliates' everyday business purposes: information about your creditworthiness
NO
N/A
For nonaffiliates to market to you
NO
N/A
Who we are
Who is providing this notice?
Michigan Educational Credit Union (MECU)
What we do
How does Michigan Educational Credit Union protect my personal information?
To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings. Encryption technology is used to keep your financial information safe.
How does Michigan Educational Credit Union collect my personal information?
We collect your personal information, for example, when you:
open an account or apply for a loan
pay your bills or deposit money
use your credit or debit card
We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.
Why can't I limit all sharing?
Federal law gives you the right to limit only:
sharing for affiliates' everyday business purposes - information about your credit worthiness
affiliates from using your information to market to you
sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you
State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.
Definitions
Affiliates
Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.
Michigan Educational Credit Union has no affiliates.
Nonaffiliates
Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.
Michigan Educational Credit Union does not share with nonaffiliates so they can market to you.
Joint Marketing
A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.
Our joint marketing partners include insurance companies and mortgage companies.
Other important information
You agree to share this Privacy Disclosure with all joint owners, joint borrowers and guarantors.
Questions?
Call 734-455-9200 or go to www.michedcu.org
Last Revised 01/2011
Go to main navigation
See All | Contract AllHomeChecking & Savings
CheckingDeposit RatesRetirement AccountsSavingsShare CertificatesLoans & Credit Cards
Auto LoansCredit CardsHome Equity LoansLoan ApplicationsLoan CalculatorLoan PaymentsLoan RatesMortgage LoansPersonal LoansVisa Signature RewardsOnline Services
Card LockCardNavCredit Card Accounts OnlineCredit SenseDigital Wallets
Samsung Pay
Apple Pay
Google Pay
Home BankingLoan PaymentsMobile BankingOnline Education CenterSpeedy LineView My MortgageZelle ®Member Services
CalculatorsCollateral Protection InsuranceFraud & SecurityFinancial Resource CenterInvestment ServicesFor SaleLost/Stolen CardsTravel NoticeTruStage Insurance ProductsWire InstructionsAbout Us
Annual ReportAwards and RecognitionCareersCommunity InvolvementFees and DisclosuresHoliday ClosingsLocations & HoursMembershipNewsletterRates
Deposit Rates
Loan Rates
Shared BranchesContact Us
